# **CECILIA MUÑOZ CARVAJAL**

# Data Analyst | Software Developer

I have a degree in Actuary with experience in both private and public sectors. I am passionate about data analysis aimed at improving processes. My purpose is to contribute to companies that respond to a sustainable mission, aligned with values that include social responsibility.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Freelance | Software developer

Feb. 2020 - Present

• Design and implement programs according to specifications, needs and use that the client wants to develop.

# **SAT - Tax Administration Service | Database Analyst**

Oct. 2018 - Jun. 2019

- Cross checking databases in Excel following revenue federal laws.
- Updating and standardizing databases.
- Supporting SQL program configuration and reporting errors to the Central Office.

### SGS - Seamless Global Solutions | Corporate Analyst

Jan. 2015 - Jul. 2017

- Strategic sales analysis and explaining key highlights to the board.
- Weekly or seasonal reports for the Sales, Marketing and Design areas.
- Forecasting and monitoring budgets and billing to clients.
- I worked as an account manager for special clients and brands.

#### GAO Comercializadora | Platform assistant

Jul. 2013 - Dec. 2014

• Implementing safety protocols and attending customer service.

### Puebla Sin Fronteras Newspaper | Web master

Sept. 2010 - Ene. 2013

• Uploading and adjusting the news to the web page everyday.

# ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

#### **Data Science Specialization / IBM**

Ago. 2020

RDBMS, cloud databases, python and SQL programming.

#### **Cybersecurity Diplomas / Universidad CLEU**

Oct. 2018, May 2019

Identify vulnerabilities of the systems and programs used in companies and personal devices; by detecting profiles and hackers behavior, through tracking and analysis of digital environments.

#### **Actuarial Science Degree / UDLAP**

Ago. 2007

Keen analytical, project management, and problem solving skills.



# CONTACT

(222) 1 33 39 75

Puebla, México.

ceciliamzcarvajal@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ceciliamz-carvajal

# **SOFTWARE**

- Excel
- Visual Basic
- Power BI
- Python
- SAP Business One
- SQL
- Retail Link and other vendors platforms.

#### COMPETENCIES

- ✓ Data visualization
- ✓ Decision making
- ✓ Goal oriented
- ✓ High sense of urgency
- ✓ Programming

### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish: Native

English: Advanced

French: Beginner